Inventory of the Archibald Woods Papers 1777-1893, 1783-1846
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Asher Jones, n.p., to Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., 11 September 1814., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 876)
  Trying to settle debt.
- Geo[rge] Paull, Zanesville, [Ohio], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 8 September 1814., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 877)
  Will send Woods his horse if cannot find a better one at fair price.
- Geo[rge] Paull, Zanesville, [Ohio], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 8 September 1814., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 877A)
  Sending Woods his horse. Will send epaulets.
- John Connell. Comm[an]d[in]g 10[th] B[rigade] Virginia M[ilitia], to A[rchibald] Woods, 4th Reg't, Virginia M[ilitia] Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 10 September 1814., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 878)
  Orders Woods to a muster.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to George Paull, Zanesville, Ohio, 16 September 1814., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 879)
  Sold sorrell horse. Has got no marching orders yet. Petitions being circulated concerning location of County seat of Monroe [County, Ohio].
- Promissory note (witnessed by Thomas Wells) of Thomas [?] with Archi[bal]d Woods,19 September 1814., 1 page. DS. (Folder 880)
- Memorandum of an agreement (witnessed by B. Fawcett) made between John Fawcett and Archi[bal]d Woods,27 September 1814., 1 page. DS. (Folder 881)
  for Fawcett acting as attorney for Samuel Cope to sell a house and lot in Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Woods.
- Bond for title from Benjamin Farquher of Clinton County, Ohio and Josiah Updegroff of Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia] to Archi[bal]d Woods of Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 30 September 1814., 2 pages. DS. (Folder 882)
  For a house and lot in Wheeling.
- Rob[er]t Woods, n.p., to Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., 9 October 1814., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 883)
  Sends what he thinks register's fees are.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to William Irwin, Richmond, Virginia, 10 October 1814., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 884)
  Sends a petition concerning militia fines. Expects lawsuit.
- The Librarian, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] Library Room to Archibald Woods, n.p., November 1814., 1 page. L. (Folder 885)
  Gives hours. Fines will be strictly enforced. All funds on hand will go to purchase books. Arrears on shares must be paid.
- John S., Baltimore, [Maryland], to Archibald Wood[s], Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 27 December 1814., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 886)
  Does not have any desire to sell land he owns in Ohio County.
- Agreement (witnessed by Franklin Woods) between Daniel Steenrod and Archi[bal]d Woods both of Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 29 December 1814. (Folder 887)
  for Woods to lease land to Steenrod.
- H. McCluny, Brooke Court House, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 1 January 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 888)
  Concerns a lawsuit [Philip] Doddridge is handling for Woods.
- General orders from Claiborne W. Gooch D[eputy] A[djutant] G[eneral] for Moses Green, A[djutant] Gen[eral]. Adjutant-General's Office, Richmond, [Virginia], 12 January 1815., 1 page. PD. (Folder 889)
  Orders 10th, 17th, 18th, and 10th Brigades to Norfolk.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to L[evi] Barber, Marietta, [Ohio], 15 January 1815., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 890)
  Makes a deposit on quarter sections. Has been at Woodfield clearing streets. Hopes to see Barber when commissioners meet to fix seat of justice for Monroe. Has been engaged marking a road to the Ohio from the new town.
- Bill of sale (witnessed by Lloyd Biddle) from Spencer Biddle to Archi[bal]d Woods,19 January 1815., 1 page. DS. (Folder 891)
  For property given to Woods by Biddle to satisfy rent that is in arrears.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to James Smith, Capteena, 23 January 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 892)
  Concerns quarter section of land Smith wants to enter. The bearers, Mr. Smith and Baker want to rent. Show them the land where Duvall lives.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Levi Barber, Marietta, [Ohio], 24 January 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 893)
  Wants to enter quarter sections.
- Alpheus P. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 30 January 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 894)
  Has been recommended as coroner of his County. Would like appointment to Woods staff. Wants appointment and hope Woods' staff are not required to march.
- Zach[aria]s Biggs, Round Bottom Mills, near Cincinnati, [Ohio] to Archebald [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 31 January 1815., 4 pages. ALS. (Folder 895)
  Jesse Hunt's brother owns land Woods is interested in. Jesse Hunt offers ten dollars per acre for land Woods owns near his brother's land. Discusses flour milling and whiskey distilling.
- Henry Stevenson, Charlestown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archib[al]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 4 February 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 896)
  Asking to be appointed surgeon to [4th] Reg't, Virginia Militia.
  Includes, LS, [4 February 1815] of John Connell. H. Marshall and W[illia]m McHenry to Woods, recommending Stevenson.
- Muster roll of a company of the 4th Regiment Virginia Militia commanded by Herman Greathouse, 9 February 1815., 2 pages. DS. (Folder 897)
- Agreement between Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., and John Cunningham, n.p., 10 February 1815, 1 page. DS. (Folder 898)
  For Woods to lease land to Cunningham.
- John Mills, n.p., to Archebald [Archibald] Woods, n.p., 11 February 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 899)
  Is satisfied that he received thirteen bushels of corn.
- And[re]w Woods, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p., 11 February 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 900)
  Adam Kellar wishes to ride home to Richmond instead of marching with rest of troops.
- James Smith, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 12 February 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 901)
  Trying to rent land for Woods.
- Muster roll of a company of the 4th Regiment, Virginia Militia commanded by William Irwin, 13 February 1815., 2 pages. DS. (Folder 902)
- Noah Zane, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to J[ohn] Marshall, Richmond, [Virginia], 14 February 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 903)
  Introduces [Archibald] Woods to Marshall.
- Appointment of John Millet as ensign in the 4th Regiment, 18th Brigade and third Division of the Virginia Militia. Signed by W[ilson] C[ary] Nicholas. Registered by J. W. Pleasants. Bears seal of Virginia, 20 February 1815. (Folder 904)
- Communication from A[rchibald] W[oods], Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to his troops in the 4th Regiment, Virginia Militia, 11 March 1815., 1 page. Copy of AMS. (Folder 905)
- W[illia]m [?], Brooke Courthouse, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 12 March 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 906)
  John Spence has been arrested for desertion. Asks for a court martial.
- Agreement (witnessed by Joshua Molliston) of Nathan Goodridge, n.p., and John Morley, n.p., with Archibald Woods, n.p., 20 March 1815., 1 page. DS. (Folder 907)
  For Woods to lease land to Goodridge and Morley.
- Ja[me]s Chapline, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to A[rchibald] Wood[s], Wheeling Creek, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 22 March 1815., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 908)
  Neither state nor federal government has funds to pay troops. Arrangements will be made to pay them at a later date.
- John Connell, Charlestown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 26 March 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 909)
  Asks Woods to remit John Spence's sentence for desertion and release him.
- Agreement (witnessed by James Smith) between James Barrett, n.p., and Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., 27 March 1815., 1 page. DS. (Folder 910)
  For Woods to lease land to Barrett and for Barrett to repair a cabin and clear land.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to Adjutant General at Washington City, [D.C.], 27 April 1815., 1 page. Copy of ALS. (Folder 911)
  Woods explains the unusual nature of his muster return due to the circumstances of their march.
- Lewis Bonnett, n.p., to Archabald [Archibald] Woods, n.p., 12 May 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 912)
  Bonnett resigns his commission as major of the 1st Battalion of the 4th Reg't of Virginia M[ilitia].
- Roll of officers of 4th Reg[i]m[en]t, [Virginia Militia], 16 May 1815., 1 page. D. (Folder 913)
- Thomas Smith, Capteena, [Ohio], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 5 July 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 914)
  Got three quarter [sections] of land.
- And[re]w Elliott, St. Louis, [Missouri],to A[rchibald] Woods,6 August 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 915)
  Woffert does not want to sell his land.
- Wil[l]iam Nolin, n.p., to Arche [Archibald] Woods, n.p., 6 August 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 916)
  Has bought land from Jacob Ash that he had no right to sell.
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia, [West Virginia], 7 August 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 917)
  Has no recollection of articles of agreement between Geo[rge] Poage and Woods.
- W[illiam] Croghan, Carlisle, Pennsylvania, to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia, [West Virginia], 15 August 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 918)
  Will stick to his terms for selling land. Asks Woods to sell his lame horse.
- Deed from John Feay (deputy sheriff acting for Basil Riggs, sheriff) to James Arbutton both of Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 22 August 1815., 1 page. DS. (Folder 919)
  For 56 acres of land sold for delinquent taxes.
- Promissory note from [Archibald Woods] and [?] with Northwestern Bank of Virginia, 2 September 1815., 1 page. D. (Folder 920)
- Rob[er]t Woods, n.p., to Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., 11 September 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 921)
  Send note against James Woods (with deed to him) to Joseph Woods.
  Includes, ALS, n.d., from J[ames] Woods to [Robert Woods?]. 1 page.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, n.p., to Moses W. Chapline, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 25 September 1815., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 922)
  Although Woods thinks settlement of Poages' claim against him made by Chapline and Thomas [Woods] is totally against him, he will agree to it.
- John McLure, Bedford, [Virginia] to James McLure, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 5 October 1815., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 923)
  Has found a slave who ran away from Archibald Woods. Has promised slave if he would return he would not be whipped.
- Benj[ami]n Jeffery, Major 4[th] Regt. Virginia M[ilitia], n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, Whelling, [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], 20 October 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 924)
  Requests commission as lieutenant for Jon Curtis if Woods has it.
- Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p., to [?] Jeffries, n.p., 23 October 1815., 1 page. Copy of ALS. (Folder 925)
  States when he wants to hold a battalion court of inquiry and a regimental court of inquiry.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to William Croghan, Ju[nio]r, Litchfield, Connecticut, 12 November 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 926)
  Does not wish to buy Croghan's land at the price Croghan named. Will sell his horse for him.
- A. Caldwell, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 23 Nov[ember 1815?]., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 927)
  Tells Woods, McCluny of Charlestown is in Wheeling if he wishes to see him.
- John Eaton, Morristown, Ohio to Archibold [Archibald] Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 23 November 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 928)
  A man wishes to buy land. Asks Woods for amount. Mr. Scot[t] wants to know if Mr. Morrison can have a set of stable logs.
- Caleb Nice, n.p., to officers of the court martial, 25 November 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 929)
  Did not know of muster until day of muster. His knee was out of place and he had no horse to ride.
- John Poage, Greenup County, [Kentucky], to Archib[a]l[d] Wood[s], near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 25 November 1815., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 930)
  Wants to make some disposition of a military land claim placed in his hands by Woods fourteen years previously.
- Agreement between Archi[bal]d Woods, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia] and Jasper Malory and John Long of Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 1 December 1815., 2 pages. D. (Folder 931)
  For Woods to lease land and ferries to Malory and Long. Malory and Long can also tap sugar maples.
- George Madison, Frankfort, [Kentucky] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 2 December 1815., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 932)
  Woods' land has been sold for taxes but can redeemed within two years of sale by paying taxes plus interest. Woods should send money for taxes for 1814 and 1815.
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington City, [D.C.] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 22 December 1815., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 933)
  Clay has drawn up petition to President to establish road to Wheeling. Meigs says tract for sale in Indiana Territory will be open for sale in April or May.
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia, [West Virginia], [1816?]., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 934)
  Will not be able to go [to Indiana Territory?]. Fears prices will be too high. A tract of his land (4066 acres in Wood County) was sold for taxes. Asks Woods to redeem.
- Memorandum of the behavior of Lydia Dill in trying to alienate W. J. Zane from his daughters, [1816?]., 1 page. M. (Folder 935)
- John Connell, B[rigadier] G[eneral], Brooke Courthouse, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Colo[nel] A[rchibald] Woods, 4th Reg[imen]t, [Virginia Militia], n.p., 8 January 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 936)
  Orders a day of training of officers and a day of regimental muster.
- Geo[rge] Miller, New York, to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 8 January 1816., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 937)
  Miller's brother does not yet know the result of his application to cob. Walker relating to lands on Green River. Discusses bank paper. Hears there is petition before Maryland legislature to establish a state bank. Has Phila[delphia] worried. Mentions possibility of a turnpike to Wheeling.
- E.C. Wilson, [Washington, D.C.], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 8 January [1816?]., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 938)
  Does not expect deposit being replaced by any act of Congress. Cumberland Road must await annual appropriation.
- L[evi] Barber, Marietta, [Ohio], to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 13 January 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 939)
  Does not have extra capital. to invest in Woodfield [Ohio].
- Samuel Wilson, n.p., to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 18 January 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 940)
  Will return a runaway slave for Woods for a fee.
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington City, [D.C.] to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia, [West Virginia], 20 January 1816., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 941)
  Decision on U.S. Road to Wheeling has been referred to Sec. of Treasury; however, Dallas is a Pennsylvanian.
- Robert Pogue, Mason County, [Kentucky], to Archabald [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 23 January 1816., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 942)
  Unable to check on Woods' land, but thinks it has been sold for taxes. Woods' mother is in her usual state of health, but her memory fails her. Gives news of his family.
- Felix Scott, Grandville, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 30 January 1816., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 943)
  Defends the assessment of Woods' land which Woods thinks is too high.
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington City, [D.C.], to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 5 February 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 944)
  Chief of Wyandot Indians is dead and his tribes are desirous of selling their lands. No report on U.S. Road. House of Representatives are now discussing direct tax. Mentions birth of a son to Mrs. Paull [Woods' daughter].
- John Reiley, n.p., to [Archibald] Woods, n.p., 18 February 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 945)
  Offers to trade money and horses for land.
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington City, [D.C.] to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 19 February 1816., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 946)
  Forwarded Woods' letter and memorial from citizens of Wheeling to Clay. James Ross and Charleston people are exciting opposition. [?] Connel has obtained depositions on a road from Charleston to Zanesville and made a statement relative to Town of Charleston. Asks Woods for depositions concerning Wheeling. Lands in Indiana not ready for sale yet.
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington, [D.C.], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], March 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 947)
  President has made a communication to both houses concerning Cumberland Road. It contains a statement of expenditure already made and those necessary to complete it. Commissioner of land office has promised a complete map of Indiana Territory. Will send to Woods.
- Samuel Parr, Vincennes, [Indiana Territory], to Archable [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 1 March 1816., 4 pages. ALS. (Folder 948)
  Describes Indiana Territory, its land, its inhabitants and prospects for the sale of the public lands.
- Moses Shepherd, City [of] Washington, [D.C.], to Archebald [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 2 March 1816. (Folder 949)
  Secretary of Treasury reported in favor of Wheeling [for u.s. Road].
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington City, [D.C.], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 2 March 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 950)
  Secretary [of Treasury] has decided in favor of Wheeling for the Cumberland Road route. Senate has passed bill for levying direct tax of three million dollars. House of Representatives is considering bank bill.
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington City,[D.C.], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 4 March 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 951)
  Secretary of Treasury reported to President on Cumberland Road, in favor of Wheeling. Mentions land tax of three million dollars. National Bank bill is under consideration in the House of Representatives. House passed bill authorizing members to frank during recess. Doesn't think it will pass Senate.
- Agreement (witnessed by Charles D. Knox and Geo[rge] Knox) between Samuel Cockayne and Archi[bal]d Woods both of Ohio County, Virginia, 6 March 1816., 1 page. DS. (Folder 952)
  For Cockayne to sell Woods two hundred acres of land in Warren County, Ohio. Woods has right to give land back.
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington City, [D.C.], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 11 March 1816., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 953)
  Has been informed that President confirmed report of Secretary of Treasury concerning the [Cumberland] Road. Exertions now will be to procure a large appropriation. Commissioners of land office cannot fix any time when land in Indiana Territory will be sold.
- Alpheus D. Willson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archib[al]d Woods, Wheeling, Ohio [County] Virginia [West Virginia], 14 March [1816]., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 954)
  Has received five dollars from Woods. Sends pantaloons back to him. Asks about his militia discharge. J. G. Jackson has declared as a candidate. Willson is coroner.
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington City, [D.C.], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 18 March 1816., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 955)
  Report on Cumberland Road has been referred to Committee in House of Representatives. Republican caucus voted Monroe and Tompkins as candidates. "on the subject of the road Monroe was decidedly your friend, his influence was important. I hope it will not be forgotten. However this subject must remain with yourself." Owing to sickness of draftsman in the land office has not been able to procure a map of the Indiana Territory.
- Zach[aria]s Biggs, Round Bottom Mills, [Ohio], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 22 March 1816., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 956)
  Two hundred acres of land bought from Sam[ue]l Cockain is worth about four dollars an acre. Discusses Capteena land owned by Jeremiah Hurst. Glad [Cumberland Road] is settled. Gives price of flour.
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington, [D.C.], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 23 March 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 957)
  The committee to whom the Cumberland Road was referred have reported in favor of the appropriation. House of Representatives laid 30 per cent ad valorem duty on imported cottons. National Bank bill is now is Senate.
- Moses Shepherd, City [of] Washington, [D.C.], to Archebald [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 24 March 1816., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 958)
  [Cumberland] Road being confirmed, he is wa[i]ting the result of the Appropriation. Connell and Doddridge still have plan for a military road. Shepherd hopes to be appointed a Superintendent, but if not wants contract for a section of it. "Mr. Clay has done all he promised but Ruggles never gave out for which I do regard him as one of our particular friends. "
- Thomas Smith, Mouth of Captinah [Capteena], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 25 March 1916., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 959)
  Would like to rent place where James Barrett lives.
- Samuel Parr, Vincennes, [Indiana], to Archable [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 26 March 1816. (Folder 960)
  Public lands have not been surveyed because Indians ordered the surveyors of f. [William Henry] Harrison owns land near Vincennes and has laid it out in town lots.
- Geo[rge] Paull, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 27 March 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 961)
  Wants to borrow $1500 to use to buy bank stock.
- Geo[rge] White, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 27 March 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 962)
  Wants to buy or borrow anvil.
- Bond for an unidentified person to pay Archi[bal]d Woods 125 dollars, 30 March 1816., 1 page. D. (Folder 963)
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington, [D.C.], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 1 April 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 964)
  Resolutions introduced to appoint committee to look into military road through Charleston. Bills passed House to admit Indiana and Mississippi as states. Nothing done on appropriation for building Cumberland Road.
- John Gardiner, General Lana Office [Washington, D.C.], to [Benjamin] Ruggles, Senate U[nited] States [Washington, D.C.], 3 April 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 965)
  Draughtsman in office is unable to attend to business. Sends sketch of Indiana Territory taken from Bradley's maps by a pupil of the draughtsman.
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Senate Chamber, [Washington, D.C.] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 3 April 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 966)
  House has passed appropriation of $300,000 for Cumberland Road.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to L[evi] Barber, Marietta [Ohio], 11 April 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 967)
  Necessary for Woods and Barber to pay up all the installments on the land Woodfield stands on so lot owners can have deeds. Wants Barber to go to Indiana with him. Wants to speculate with Barber's interest in Woodfield.
- W[illia]m Irwin, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods,[Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], 13 April 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 968)
  Resigns his commission as captain in the Wheeling Light Infantry.
- John Richardson, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to A[rchibald] Woods,17 April 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 969)
  Asks to borrow $160.